ADAM VIGEANT

UX DESIGNER I DESIGN THINKER



CONTACT

603-321-3749



AdamVigeantUX@gmail.com



AVigeant.com



linkedin.com/in/adam-vigeant/

UX SKILLS

- Design Thinking
- User-Centered Design (UCD)
- UI & Visual Design
- Wireframes & Prototyping
- User Experience Research
- Design Personas
- User Flows
- Journey Maps
- Information Architecture (IA)
- Usability Testing
- Interaction Design

TOOLS

- Adobe CC (Creative Cloud)
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe XD
- Axure
- Balsamiq
- Omnigraffle
- InVision
- Sketch
- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript

PROFILE

User Experience Designer with a passion to solve challenging problems. A capable and empathetic mediator between client, business, and development teams, with creative problem-solving abilities rooted in Design Thinking.

Experienced in UX best practices with awareness of the psychological and human factors that influence design. Adam is a well-rounded, collaborative, and effective teammate with over 10 years experience in graphic and interaction design.

EXPERIENCE

UX & VISUAL DESIGN CONTRACTOR

AV Design | 2011-Present

- Designed over 10 unique brand identities in addition to numerous web, graphic, and informational deliverables.
- Collaborated with clients to implement design solutions that meet specific user needs and vision.
- · Implemented effective communication, timemanagement, and organizational strategy to ensure high-quality work.
- Communicated with businesses and translated complex problems into understandable action-steps.
- Improved effectiveness of designs through researching and implementing UX tools, techniques, and best practices for optimum usability and accessibility.

DESIGN CONSULTANT

Powell Prints | 2015-2021

- Curated over 300 visual designs for customers, preserving brand guidelines and budget/time constraints.
- Balanced needs of management, product production, and customers to produce effective design solutions.
- Utilized Design Thinking to develop creative solutions to address business and client needs.
- Advised management and production teams on current design trends and implemented workflow improvements.
- Facilitated client meetings to identify needs, build relational equity, and establish project parameters.

EDUCATION

Certification in UX Design & Frontend Development

CareerFoundry | 2020-2021

Bachelor of Science in Media Design

Indiana Wesleyan University | 2009-2013